Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we're
talking about something that I think a
lot of people experience, especially
with certain things like peanuts and cats.
So what are we talking about?
That's right. Today we are talking
about allergies. So that means that we
have a problem with maybe cats.
They make us sick or with certain foods.
Like a lot of people who
are allergic to milk, actually.
That's right. So we're going to talk about
a couple of these allergies and symptoms.
So why don't we have a listen to
our dialogue and we'll be back in a bit.
Oh, I feel terrible. I keep sneezing and my
eyes are all watery. What's wrong with me?
Wow, you're not dying. Are
you? Looks like you have a cold.
You should take some medicine.
I don't think it's a cold. I feel fine if I
move a few feet away from my desk.
Maybe we should put you in the quarantine.
Jokes aside, I think you
might have an allergy.
An allergy? I never thought about that.
I don't think I'm allergic
to pollen though and I'm
desensitized to bee stings
after being stung so many times.
Oh! Why did you chuck that peanut at me?
Just checking if you're
allergic to peanuts, I guess not.
Not funny.
I could have gone into anaphylactic shock.
Okay, my bad. How about dust?
This office is full of it.
Yes, the whole office is dusty, yet
I only feel affected in your desks.
You brought your cat into the office?
Yeah, it's Mr. Snuffles'
birthday today.
I didn't want it to be
alone on a special day.
Ah, put it away!
I guess we found the problem.
You're allergic to cats.
Alright, so now let's take a look
at vocab on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Alright, so Marco, we have a
number of things that might
happen if you're feeling like
you're allergic to something.
The first one is, my eyes are all watery.
Okay, so your eyes get
watery and that means you start
to have a lot of water, a
lot of tears in your eyes.
That's right, but you're not sad. You're
not crying. It's just that you have this
reaction that you cannot control and the
water maybe comes down from your eyes.
Right, usually it gets your eyes get wet
and watery, itchy red, so a lot of that.
There's another thing
too. This happens a lot.
You feel like you can't
stop sneezing to sneeze.
A sneeze is something you do
when the air comes out of your nose.
And you can't control it and
sometimes it's very, very strong.
You move your head, but it's something that
you do when you're allergic to something like
cat or flower, but also maybe when you smell
something very some spice like a hot pepper.
Yeah, or when you're sick when
you have a cold. That's right.
And so his friend says that maybe
they should put him into quarantine.
All right, now this is a joke.
If you have allergies, you
don't have to go to quarantine,
but quarantine is very serious.
It's a place where people go when they have
a dangerous or very infectious disease.
Right.
And quarantine means that no one
else can come in and you cannot go out.
Right, exactly. So I think when they
had the pig flew, the swine flew, many
people were put into quarantine to make
sure they didn't give it to someone else.
That's right. So usually in
quarantine, you have to wait until you
can prove that you're not sick
anymore and then you get to leave.
That's right. All right.
So they were talking about maybe
the options of what he is allergic to.
He says, I'm not, I don't
think I'm allergic to pollen.
So what is pollen?
Where does it come from?
All right. Now pollen is actually very
common allergy and pollen comes from flowers.
It's kind of like a special
dust or special kind of
thing that you see on
flowers that gets blown away.
So when it's springtime,
many people suffer from
allergies because there's
a lot more pollen in the air.
So it's that little dust usually
sometimes yellow that you can find
on flowers and this is actually
what butterflies and bees look for.
That's right. Okay.
And then he talked about, well,
he's not allergic to bees and his
friend threw a peanut at him,
but he said it in a very strange way.
He said, why did you chuck
that peanut at me to try to chuck?
Now this is a very spoken English way of
saying something to chuck means to throw.
So like Marco, why did
you chuck that pillow at me?
That was mean.
All right. So to chuck is to throw, but
usually to throw something strongly.
So as you said, it's very spoken
English is not really proper
to actually write it or say it to
someone in a formal occasion.
Yeah, that's right. So you
wouldn't say this in your
English exam, but you could
say this with your friends.
Okay, so to chuck something.
So that's all the
vocab we have for you.
Why don't we go back and
listen to the dialogue again.
Oh, I feel terrible.
I keep sneezing in my eyes are all watery.
What's wrong with me?
Wow, you're not dying. Are
you? Looks like you have a cold.
You should take some medicine.
I don't think it's a cold. I feel fine if I
move a few feet away from my desk.
Maybe we should put you into quarantine.
Jokes aside, I think you
might have an allergy.
An allergy?
I never thought about that.
I don't think I'm allergic
to pollen though, and I'm
desensitized to bee stings
after being stung so many times.
Hmm.
Ow! Why did you chuck that peanut at me?
Just checking if you were
allergic to peanuts, I guess not.
Not funny.
I could have gone into anaphylactic shock.
Okay, my bad. How about dust?
This office is full of it.
Yes, the whole office is dusty, yet
I only feel affected in your desks.
You brought your cat into the office?
Yeah, it's Mr. Snuffles
birthday today.
I didn't want him to be
alone on his special day.
Ah, put it away!
I guess we found the problem.
You're allergic to cats.
All right, we're back, so now
it's time for Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
All right, now we heard a very
difficult word later on in the dialogue.
Jim said, "Not funny. I could
have gone into anaphylactic shock.
" Right.
All right, so this phrase, "to
go into shock" is very important.
Go into shock.
Now, what does it mean to go into shock?
Well, shock is something,
especially anaphylactic shock,
which means that I think
you can stop breathing
because your body
basically shuts down.
You can't, you know, you throw
out titans you can't breathe.
But to go into shock
means that your body
will kind of stop doing
its normal functions.
For example, if you've fallen very, very
cold water, your body goes into shock.
Right.
And this is something
that is a physical reaction.
You see it all the time in
movies, I think, when a nurse or
a doctor or someone yells,
"He's going into shock," right?
That's right, and they have
to get the paddles and beep.
Right, exactly.
So that's what it means
when you go into shock,
but you use this verb, you go into shock.
He's going into shock.
That's right, doctor. He's gone into shock.
Uh-huh. And, well, he said,
"Okay, I'm sorry. My bad.
" He said, "My bad.
What is my bad?"
All right, "My bad" is another
phrase that comes from spoken English
to be careful with how you use it. This is
something you can use with your friends.
"My bad" is a way
of saying, "My fault.
" Or, "Excuse me, you
know, that mistake.
" "My mistake."
So, if you do something wrong and you
say, "Oh, I'm sorry, that was my mistake.
" You can just say, "Oh, my bad.
" That's right. Or, you know, Jerry,
can we go outside for a second?
I have to talk to you.
I mean, Marco, my bad.
Right, exactly.
That means I'm, you know, on my fault.
I'm sorry, I've made a mistake.
So, but this is very colloquial
and I think it's very juvenile, right?
I think, uh, younger
people use this, my bad.
"My bad.
" Yeah, it's, it's
younger. Yeah.
That's a younger. All right.
And, uh, for our last
phrase when Jim was
talking about maybe
being allergic to pollen,
or he said, "I'm
desensitized to bee stings.
" All right, so desensitized. You should
know automatically that prefix D means not.
Mm-hmm. All right, so it's negative.
I'm desensitized means
that I'm not sensitive to.
All right. That means that, you
know, if I get stung by a bee, like me,
it gets big and red and it hurts.
Right.
But this person, he doesn't
have a reaction. He's desensitized.
So, there's no reaction.
There's no red. There's no swelling.
I think, uh, you see it a lot,
uh, for people that maybe
live in an area where there
are a lot of mosquitoes.
Mm-hmm. And if we go there, we're going to
get bitten and, uh, it's going to be itchy.
But people who live there,
they've been bitten so
many times that they
probably don't even feel it,
or probably don't even get
bitten in, or they desensitized.
That's right. Or you could say
that I'm desensitized to loud noises.
Okay. I live in a city, and there's a,
there's a metro near my apartment.
Mm-hmm. Yeah, I can hear it.
It's very loud.
Uh-huh.
And so I'm desensitized to the noise.
That means I don't really notice
it anymore. It doesn't bother me.
Right. Very good. So that's all the vocab
and phrases we've prepared for you today.
Let's listen to this
dialogue one last time.
Oh, I feel terrible.
I keep sneezing in my eyes, roe-watery.
What's wrong with me?
Wow, you're not dying. Are you?
Looks like you have a cold.
You should take some medicine.
I don't think it's a cold. I feel fine if I
move a few feet away from my desk.
Maybe we should put you in the quarantine.
Jokes aside, I think you
might have an allergy.
An allergy? I never thought about that.
I don't think I'm allergic
to pollen, though,
and I'm desensitized to bee stings
after being stung so many times.
Hmm. Oh!
Why did you chuck that peanut at me?
Just checking if you're
allergic to peanuts, I guess not.
Not funny.
I could have gone into anaphylactic shock.
Okay, my bad. How about dust?
This office is full of it.
Yes, the whole office is dusty, yet
I only feel affected in your desks.
You brought your cat into the office?
Yeah, it's Mr. Snuffles'
birthday today.
I didn't want it to be
alone on a special day.
Ah, put it away!
I guess we found the problem.
You're allergic to cats.
All right, so speaking about allergies,
we always talk about the
common ones, like a pollen dust.
And you also mentioned about food,
like somebody who cannot drink milk.
They're allergic to milk.
That's right.
We have a special name for this, actually.
Someone who cannot
drink milk or dairy products
like ice cream is called
lactose intolerant.
So, if you're lactose
intolerant, it means that your
stomach is very upset after
you have dairy products.
Because lactose is basically dairy.
And there are some people
also who are allergic to seafood,
for example, fish or shrimp
or any type of seafood.
That's right, and also people
who are allergic to gluten.
A gluten is a very common product
that is found in breads and cereal.
Things like that. And so,
people who have an allergy to
gluten actually have to
change their diet quite a bit.
Yeah, they have to look for
things that are gluten-free,
which is very hard because
apparently it's in everything.
That's right. So, if you have
one of these allergies, you
can find dairy-free on a
box or gluten-free on the box.
And specialty food stores
will have these labels.
And so, are you allergic to anything?
No, not really. Sometimes in here, in China,
I feel like I'm a little bit allergic.
I have allergies when the seasons change.
Uh-huh.
But at home, no.
I have no allergies.
No allergies, no, me neither.
And I can, I'm very lucky,
I think, because I can't
imagine if I had an allergy
like to peanuts or to seafood,
which not only would be a shame
because you can't have these foods,
but if you accidentally have
it, it could be life-threatening.
That's right. Like my dad,
who is allergic to bees,
would go into anaphylactic
shock if he were stung.
And so, you have to be
very careful because you
never know when you'll
have an accident like that.
Exactly.
So, this is an interesting topic.
Maybe you guys want to share
if you are allergic to anything.
Maybe you are allergic to
certain types of foods, chemicals.
Some people are allergic to certain
types of shampoo, for example.
Or fabrics like cotton.
Uh-huh.
So, if you want to share with us, let us
know at our website, www.EnglishPod.com.
We'll see you guys there. Bye.
[Music]